<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: pol | TIFI]]></title>
  <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/tags/pol/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-25T18:29:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://akda5id.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Forecast 2010]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2009/12/28/forecast-2010/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-28T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2009/12/28/forecast-2010</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>James Howard Kunstler on his excellently titled blog <a href="http://kunstler.com/blog/2009/12/forecast-2010.html">Clusterfuck Nation</a>:</p>

<blockquote>One wild card is how angry the American people might get.  Unlike the 1930s, we are no longer a nation who call each other "Mister" and "Ma'am," where even the down-and-out wear neckties and speak a discernible variant of regular English, where hoboes say "thank you," and where, in short, there is something like a common culture of shared values.  We're a nation of thugs and louts with flames tattooed on our necks, who call each other "motherfucker" and are skilled only in playing video games based on mass murder. The masses of Roosevelt's time were coming off decades of programmed, regimented work, where people showed up in well-run factories and schools and pretty much behaved themselves. In my view, that's one of the reasons that the US didn't explode in political violence during the Great Depression of the 1930s - the discipline and fortitude of the citizenry.  The sheer weight of demoralization now is so titanic that it is very hard to imagine the people of the USA pulling together for anything beyond the most superficial ceremonies - placing teddy bears on a crash site.  And forget about discipline and fortitude in a nation of ADD victims and self-esteem seekers.</blockquote>


<p><a href="http://kunstler.com/blog/2009/12/forecast-2010.html">Note, I broke my pub system, so you must click this to read through, will fix my shit sometime after new years and get posting again.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[20,000 Nations Above the Sea]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2009/08/22/20000-nations-above-the-sea/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2009/08/22/20000-nations-above-the-sea</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Friedman wondered: What if you could just move—not just you, but everything you own, including your home, and, if your neighbors agreed with you, your whole community? What if you could move all of it where no government would bother you at all, and you could make a new, better society?</blockquote>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mirror, Mirror on the Wall]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2009/01/27/mirror-mirror-on-the-wall/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-27T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2009/01/27/mirror-mirror-on-the-wall</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Errol Morris:</p>

<blockquote>
During the last week of the Bush administration, I asked the head photo editors of these news services &#8212; Vincent Amalvy (AFP), Santiago Lyon (AP) and Jim Bourg (Reuters) &#8212; to pick the photographs of the president that they believe captured the character of the man and of his administration.
</blockquote>


<p>Via <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2009/01/26/mirror-mirror">Daring Fireball</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Sun Should Do]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/11/25/what-sun-should-do/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/11/25/what-sun-should-do</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2008/11/24/What-Sun-Should-Do" title="ongoing &#xb7; What Sun Should Do">Tim Bray</a> on Sun:</p>

<blockquote>Sun is going through a lousy spell right now. Well, so is the world’s economy in general and the IT business in particular, but this is about Sun. This is my opinion about what my employer should do about it. [. . .] Sun should adopt a laser focus on building a Sun Web Suite and becoming the Web application deployment platform of choice. It’s a large space, a growing space, and one where we can win.</blockquote>


<p>He is obviously absolutely right, there is no place for the old Sun in this world. However Sun does have some excellent tech, and importantly they seem to still have a lot of top engineers, so if they can manage a major restructuring they have a fighting chance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shirky on Coase, Collaboration and Here Comes Everybody]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/10/20/shirky-on-coase-collaboration-and-here-comes-everybody/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/10/20/shirky-on-coase-collaboration-and-here-comes-everybody</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Clay Shirky, author of Here Comes Everybody: The Power of Organizing Without Organizations, talks about the economics of organizations with EconTalk host Russ Roberts. The conversation centers on Shirky's book. Topics include Coase on the theory of the firm, the power of sharing information on the internet, the economics of altruism, and the creation of Wikipedia.</blockquote>


<p>And a great bit of discussion on representative vs. direct democracy and the possibility that networks can enable direct democracy.</p>

<p>Via <a href="http://econlog.econlib.org/archives/2008/10/clay_shirky_pod.html">EconLog</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
