<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: tech | TIFI]]></title>
  <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/tags/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-25T18:29:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://akda5id.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weapons of Mass Destruction]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2009/02/04/weapons-of-mass-destruction/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-04T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2009/02/04/weapons-of-mass-destruction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.photographyserved.com/Gallery/Weapons-of-Mass-Destruction/56260" title="Weapons of Mass Destruction  ::  Photography Served"><img src="http://s3.ubernerd.org/blog/2009/02/574921201017440.jpg"></a>
"Little Boy" (Hiroshima Atomic Bomb) 1945</p>

<p>Nice set of black and white (and infrared?) photos of cold war era Weapons of Mass Destruction.</p>

<p>See also: <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2008/12/15/081215fa_fact_samuels?printable=true" title="A Reporter at Large: Atomic John: Reporting & Essays: The New Yorker">"Atomic John" in The New Yorker</a></p>

<blockquote>The single, blinding release of pure energy over Hiroshima, Japan, on August 6, 1945, marked a startling and permanent break with our prior understandings of the visible world. Yet for more than sixty years the technology behind the explosion has remained a state secret.</blockquote>


<blockquote>The most accurate account of the bomb’s inner workings—an unnervingly detailed reconstruction, based on old photographs and documents—has been written by a sixty-one-year-old truck driver from Waukesha, Wisconsin, named John Coster-Mullen, who was once a commercial photographer, and has never received a college degree.</blockquote>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Engineering Evaluation of SHA-3 candidates]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/12/11/an-engineering-evaluation-of-sha-3-candidates/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-11T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/12/11/an-engineering-evaluation-of-sha-3-candidates</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Niels [Ferguson, of the Skein team] has started a page of SHA-3 engineering comparisons.</blockquote>


<p>Yes, they are biased, but I still trust the results.</p>

<p>Via <a href="http://www.schneier.com/blog/archives/2008/12/more_sha-3_news.html">Schneier on Security</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beijing Cubism: How ETFE Revolutionized the Bubble]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/12/03/beijing-cubism-how-etfe-revolutionized-the-bubble/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-03T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/12/03/beijing-cubism-how-etfe-revolutionized-the-bubble</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>ETFE is temperature-resistant, lightweight (1/100th the weight of glass), recyclable, non-toxic when exposed to flame (it actually shrinks away from heat, thus helping to vent smoke out of a burning building), highly insulative, non-porous, and non-stick. Even better, its high-tensile strength makes it easy to manipulate—it can be spun into thin sheets for ease of transport then inflated on-site to create the "pillow" effect of the Aquatics Center walls. It can also be finished in varying degrees of translucence—as transparent as glass or opaque as glass bricks.</blockquote>


<p>Via at <a href="http://www.cityofsound.com/">cityofsound</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Sun Should Do]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/11/25/what-sun-should-do/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/11/25/what-sun-should-do</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.tbray.org/ongoing/When/200x/2008/11/24/What-Sun-Should-Do" title="ongoing &#xb7; What Sun Should Do">Tim Bray</a> on Sun:</p>

<blockquote>Sun is going through a lousy spell right now. Well, so is the world’s economy in general and the IT business in particular, but this is about Sun. This is my opinion about what my employer should do about it. [. . .] Sun should adopt a laser focus on building a Sun Web Suite and becoming the Web application deployment platform of choice. It’s a large space, a growing space, and one where we can win.</blockquote>


<p>He is obviously absolutely right, there is no place for the old Sun in this world. However Sun does have some excellent tech, and importantly they seem to still have a lot of top engineers, so if they can manage a major restructuring they have a fighting chance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shirky on Coase, Collaboration and Here Comes Everybody]]></title>
    <link href="http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/10/20/shirky-on-coase-collaboration-and-here-comes-everybody/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://akda5id.github.com/blog/2008/10/20/shirky-on-coase-collaboration-and-here-comes-everybody</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Clay Shirky, author of Here Comes Everybody: The Power of Organizing Without Organizations, talks about the economics of organizations with EconTalk host Russ Roberts. The conversation centers on Shirky's book. Topics include Coase on the theory of the firm, the power of sharing information on the internet, the economics of altruism, and the creation of Wikipedia.</blockquote>


<p>And a great bit of discussion on representative vs. direct democracy and the possibility that networks can enable direct democracy.</p>

<p>Via <a href="http://econlog.econlib.org/archives/2008/10/clay_shirky_pod.html">EconLog</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
